Now Carrie just spent a lot of time talking about how can you use
Carrie 花了很长时间谈论如何使用
external data?
外部数据
But there's also a question about how we can use our own data, or
但还有一个问题 我们如何使用我们自己的数据
basically do it ourselves.
或使其成为我们自己的数据
Right?
对吧？
So there's sort of two classes of methods.
有两种方法
Now one class of method basically uses all of our existing data.
一种方法是使用我们现有的所有数据
If you're running experiments, you probably have existing logs or
如果你正在进行实验 你可能拥有现有日志
data capture that you're using to measure metrics, and
或捕获的数据 你可以使用它们测量指标
sort of track your business.
并跟踪你的业务
And so it's going to be a set of techniques that are going to use
因此 这是使用现有数据
that set of existing data,
进行回顾性分析和实验
both retrospective analyses, as well as running experiments.
的一套技巧
We'll be going over those next.
我们之后会谈论这个
Now the other class of methods are when you want to gather new data.
另一种方法是 你想要收集新数据
Now these are going to be methods that you'll use when you want to
当你想回答在你的现有数据中找不到答案的问题时
answer questions that you can't really answer from your existing data.
你使用这些方法
The main techniques here are going to be things like,
主要技巧包括
user experience research, surveys, and focus groups.
用户体验研究、调查和焦点小组
And Caroline,
Caroline
I think you're going to going over those in more detail in the next video, right?
我想在下一个视频中你会详细介绍这些 对吗？
>> Yeah.
是的
>> So let's talk a minute about what you can do with your own external
那我们花一分钟的时间来谈谈你能够使用你网站上的这些外部记录数据
logging data, or data capture, from your site.
或捕获的数据做些什么
So first you can do what's called retrospective, or
首先 你能做的是回顾性或
observational analysis, where you look at how a metric you're interested in, or
观察性分析 你可以查看你感兴趣的指标
just measurements you take from your site, change in response to changes
或者测量由于过去的更改导致的网站变更
you've made in the past, experiments you've run, big spikes in your business.
运行过的实验 业务高峰
So that's good to get a baseline, and it can also help you develop theories.
因此 这对于得到一个基准十分有用 并且能够帮助你制定理论
You can also use this data in conjunction with other methods,
你还可以将这个数据和其他方法
such as surveys or user experience research,
如调查或用户体验研究一同使用
to help you develop ideas of what you want to look at.
从而帮助你开发你想要的创意
So for example, if you had a bunch of students in a lab doing a survey, or
例如 如果你聚集很多学员在实验室中进行调查
a focus group, and you could see that they were all getting stuck on
或焦点小组访谈 然后看到他们都
a particular quiz, that might make you suspicious.
卡在特定的测试题上 你可能会怀疑
And you won't actually use your logs to analyze, hey you know,
你不会使用日志分析
how does this quiz behave, compared to other quizzes?
和其他测试题相比 这道测试题怎么样？
How long are people taking, so on and so forth.
人们花费多长时间等问题
The problem with these studies is that they're really, show you correlations,
研究的这个问题实际上说明相关性
not necessarily causation.
不一定是因果关系
Because you're not running a parallel A versus B, or
因为你不运行平行的 A 和 B 实验 或
A versus B versus C versus D experiment.
A、B、C、D 对比实验
It's really hard to establish that the change you made
很难确定你实施的更改实际上会发生什么
actually caused what happened, and it's not some funny temporal effect.
而这并不是有趣的暂时的效应
So that's an important difference between doing this type of experiment,
运行这种类型的试验
or doing this type of analysis, and doing a real structured experiment.
或这种类型的分析和运行一个真实结构化的实验之间 存在很重要的差异
>> As Carrie said, using retrospective analysis is really best for
Carrie 说过 使用回顾性分析
establishing a correlation and not a causation.
对于建立相关性而不是因果关系非常有用
So one method that we can use to validate metrics
因此 我们能够用于验证指标的一个方法是
is actually running experiments.
进行实验
Now this may seem horribly circular.
现在 这看起来十分迂回
We're going to run an experiment to validate whether or
我们要进行一个实验
not we can use a metric for evaluating experiments?
验证我们是否能够使用一个指标评估实验
The thing is that, what we want to do is we want to measure
事实是 我们想要测量
that the metric is actually going to move as we make changes.
我们进行修改时 指标是如何变化的
So using Carrie's example, if we're using the length of time it takes for
因此 使用 Carrie 的示例 如果我们使用学员完成一道测试题的
a student to complete a quiz as a metric for whether or not that quiz is actually
时间长度作为这道测试题是否是
going to be a good measure of students understand that material, then
学员能够理解材料的一个良好的衡量指标
we have to actually test out and say, okay, well I'm going to try this quiz,
然后我们必须进行测试 然后说 好的 我要测试这道测试题
and this other quiz, and I'm going to try a completely different formulation.
和另一道测试题 我要尝试一种完全不同的构想
And compare all of those different quizzes and say,
对所有这些不同的测试题进行比较
okay, well, which ones of them actually move my proposed metric?
然后找出 哪些测试题改变了我的指标？
Now we're going to talk about how we use this method more when we talk about
现在 我们要谈谈 在这节课后面我们谈论
sensitivity and robustness, later on in this lesson.
敏感性和稳健性时 我们将如何更深入地使用这个方法
>> Now, the other thing you shouldn't forget is to talk to your colleagues,
现在 你不应该忘记的另一件事是和你的同事讨论
because they have great ideas, or may have worked in other companies that
因为他们有很棒的想法 或在使用不同指标的其他公司工作过
use different metrics, or worked in research.
或从事过研究工作
And so you should talk to them about
因此你应该和他们讨论
what ideas they think make sense for metrics.
他们认为什么想法对这些指标十分有用
And then, the other thing is, of course,
当然 另一件事是
you want to think about your company's culture.
想想公司的文化
Some companies don't want, necessarily, the people developing the website
有些公司不一定要求开发网站的员工
to think about how much revenue they're bringing in,
考虑他们能够为公司带来多少效益
they want to see innovative features.
他们想要看到创造性特征
And then other companies are very focused on obtaining market share and
有些公司则非常注重获得市场份额
adding users, where as, you know, another,
增加用户 而还有一些公司
a different company might want to just make their existing users happier.
只是想使其现有的用户更快乐
So it's really important to take into account your corporate culture as you
因此 确定业务指标时 考虑你所在公司的文化
define your business metrics.
真的很重要
>> That makes sense.
有道理
Do you usually only use one of these methods at a time?
你平时一次只使用一个方法吗？
>> You can, but
可以
it's usually more robust to triangulate between different methods.
但使不同的方法呈三角关系通常会更稳健
So for example, let's say that you wanted to see
例如 你想知道
if students are really happy with your website.
学员是否真的喜欢使用你的网站
So in our audacity experiment, we want to say well,
因此 在我们 Audacity 的实验中
are we, are we seeing signs of happiness?
我们看到快乐的迹象了吗？
So first you might look through your logs and say, given that somebody took
因此 首先你可能会仔细检查你的日志 然后说 让一个学员参加第二门课程
a second course, which we'll say is being happy, what did they do?
我们认为这就是快乐 他们会怎么做呢？
How long did they spend?
他们会花费多长时间？
How many months were they active on the site?
他们在网站上能够活跃几个月？
You want to get some baseline for that.
你想要获得一些判断的基准
And then given that they took a second course,
考虑到他们参加了第二门课程
then you might also want to trigger surveys that happened within your site,
你还想在你的网站上进行调查
or do a focus group, where people who've done a single course, actually
或对已经完成了一门课程的用户进行焦点小组访谈
get a survey that says, you know, are you considering taking a second course?
调查他们会考虑参加第二门课程吗？
Were you happy with the first course?
你对第一门课程满意吗？
And that can give you, maybe not a lot of data, but some idea of whether they
他们可能不会给你很多数据 而是他们是否感觉快乐
were happy, and how that relates to taking a second course.
以及他们的快乐与他们参加第二门课程的关系
So it's usually a good idea to try to lay out the boundaries around
因此 尝试给你的指标划定范围
your metric.
是一个很好的主意
You won't ever get exactly the same results from a couple of different
不同的技巧不会得到完全一样的结果
techniques, but they can really give you a good sense, in conjunction,
但这些结果能给你一些很好的信息
of what you might be missing, and what the right things to measure are.
比如你丢失了什么以及应该测量什么